Drew Holbrook

Summary

I'm a software engineer based in Crested Butte, Colorado. I'm a co-creator of Ekko, an open-source realtime service with in-transit message processing. I have multiple years of experience with the Ruby and Javascript ecosystems and am comfortable with AWS and Docker.

Professional Experience

2021 - present

Co-Creator, Software Engineer

Ekko ☑

Ekko is an open-source framework that allows developers to easily deploy a realtime infrastructure for web applications. Custom serverless functions provide a flexible, modular way to process messages as they pass through the realtime system.

- Built the WebSocket server using Node.js, Socket.IO, and Redis
- Designed the AWS cloud infrastructure to support tens of thousands of websocket connections (Application Load Balancer, ECS Fargate, S3, Elasticache, Lambda)
- Containerized the server code for deployment (Docker, Elastic Container Registry)
- Automated the infrastructure deployment using AWS Cloud Development Kit
- Built an easy-to-use CLI tool for AWS credential configuration, infrastructure deployment, teardown, and Lambda management (oclif, JavaScript, AWS SDK)
- Load tested the real-time service using artillery.io on 4 EC2s to simulate 50,000 concurrent connections publishing 300,000 messages per minute
- Collaborated daily with a team of fully remote engineers
- Co-authored Ekko's case study: ekko-realtime.com ☑

2018 - 2021

Full-Stack Web Developer

Self Employed

- RequestBin: An app for viewing WebhHooks (Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL)
- Ello: A Trello-like collaboration app (React/Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB)
- Todo List: a todo tracker (Node.js, Express, JavaScript, Handlebars, HTML and CSS)
- Book Viewer: an eBook Reader (Sinatra, ERB, HTML, CSS)

2015 - 2018

Director of Marketing and Development

Crested Butte Nordic

Revamped marketing plan which helped increase revenue by 26.7% over three years

2014 - 2015

Director of Events

Crested Butte Nordic

Managed over 100 volunteers and organized events for more than 1000 participants

Skills

Back-End	Front-End	Tooling	Cloud
Node.js/Express,	JavaScript,	Git/GitHub,	AWS (ALB, EC2, ECR, ECS,
Ruby/Sinatra,	React/Redux,	Docker,	Fargate, IAM, Lambda,
PostgreSQL, MongoDB,	Handlebars, ERB,	Linux	S3, SDK),
REST APIs, Go	HTML/CSS, JQuery		Digital Ocean, Heroku

Education

2004 - 2008

B.A. Economics